<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://suhee-cho.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://suhee-cho.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-21T22:39:25+00:00</updated><id>https://suhee-cho.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Suhee Cho</title><entry><title type="html">Prologue</title><link href="https://suhee-cho.github.io/blog/2026/prologue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prologue"/><published>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://suhee-cho.github.io/blog/2026/prologue</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://suhee-cho.github.io/blog/2026/prologue/"><![CDATA[<h4 id="howdy-readers">Howdy, readers!</h4> <p>I’d like to call this blog space a <strong>project</strong>. A project to write about my thoughts and leave them as a record, mainly for my future self as a reader, but also to inspire other people who are in research, writing, or who simply enjoy reading someone’s observations about the world.</p> <p>The reason why I’m tagging this small webpage and these pieces of writing as grand “project” mainly stems from my language background. I was born and raised in South Korea, with Korean as my first language. Before entering college, I’d never imagined myself speaking anything other than Korean as my main language of daily conversation.</p> <p>A small fortune here is that I have been exposed to English since I was very young — English had been a part of the mandatory curriculum since I was in 3rd grade. But honestly speaking, it was far outside the boundary of my interest. Let’s put it this way: I’ve seen multiple math nerds in school. They were super cool kids who understand the abstract concepts and were proficient at playing with them. I’ve seen Korean nerds as well. In fact, I identified myself as one of them and was even proud of being so, since I viewed ourselves as emotionally rich and intelligent to express our thoughts and feelings in much deeper resolution. But English nerds? Well, first of all, I’d barely seen any, and second of all, ‘Hmm… what’s cool about being good at English?’</p> <p>Things flipped dramatically as I decided to live in the United States for a year, studying at Georgia Tech as an exchange student. When I first arrive in Atlanta, I realized I didn’t even know how to order coffee in English. It was very uncanny, especially since I’d been learning English ever since I was a nine-year-old. I had even taken college-level classes in English. My TOEFL score was good enough to allow me to apply for this exchange program. But all those things I just laid out were focused on academic English. In real-life scenes in the United States, you are supposed to speak something different.</p> <p>This caused me some practical problems that bothered me a lot in my early phase as a non-native exchange student. As soon as I landed at Atlanta airport —first time breathing the air in the States! Yay! — I realized my unskilled communication caused a serious issue in completing the apartment lease. It was as late as 10 pm, with two huge suitcases by my side, I realized I had no shelter to lay my exhausted body. I spent the night homeless in midtown Atlanta . What an ultimate American experience a first-time newcomer can have! I was finally able to win my bedroom key late the next afternoon, after a long, tedious quarrel with the leasing officer. Not only did the officer have a hard time understanding my Korean accent, but also I couldn’t get her Southern accent. I later learned that the accent I heard in my childhood English class was only spoken by white people in Boston.</p> <p>Despite all the awkward and unpleasant struggles, I would describe being proficient in a second language after you’re mature enough to observe the evolution of your language ability is a truly enjoyable journey. It’s fascinating to observe your second language space emerge and being more and more independent from the space of your mother tongue.</p> <p>What do I mean by <em>independent</em>? Well, before talking about that, I would like to differentiate thoughts from words or languages.</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <h4 id="relationship-between-thoughts-and-languages">Relationship between thoughts and languages</h4> <p>Thought is something very abstract. It not only includes logical thinking that you build step-by-step but also embraces feelings and emotions. As a neuroscientists, I would describe it as a pattern of neuronal firing in your brain.</p> <p>On the other hand, language is a tool for expressing these thoughts. (In fact, there are multiple ways of expressing your thoughts, aside from language: we can dance, draw, sing, or even wink. There is extremely interesting line of research employing different modes of expression done by an excellent faculty member in my department. Shout out to Dr. Judy Fan!!) People sometimes ask me whether I think in Korean or English. I think this question doesn’t quite make sense. I don’t necessarily think in either Korean or English. I just… feel the thoughts without wording them.</p> <p>A caveat here. Since language is one way of expressing abstract thoughts, it often does not represent them fully. It’s this simple: Can we explain what the color red is like to a blind person? Well, we can explain the wavelength of the light. We can say it is FF0000 in hex code and (1, 0, 0) in RGB. But is that truly representing red? No, there’s something that each description misses. This is where a struggle of many bilinguals come from: “I don’t like what I just said in English. That’s not quite accurate description of what I’m thinking. If I were to speak Korean, I could’ve described my thought more precisely… Darn!”</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <h4 id="relationship-between-different-languages">Relationship between different languages</h4> <p>Learning a second language is totally different from learning your mother tongue, because the language you newly learn highly depends on the languages you already speak. On the first day of my English class, the teacher taught me that “<em>Hello</em> means <em>안녕하세요</em>!” I also remember that I had a workbook full of widely used English words alongside Korean words with the same (or, I should say, the most similar) meanings.</p> <p>The key point I wanted to make here is that, my English skills were initially built upon a pre-existing language foundation—Korean. My communication in English was impossible without Korean playing a mediator role. When I wanted to express something in English, I first conceived a thought, then put that thought into Korean, and then translated it into English. It was extremely slow and inaccurate, as I mentioned earlier, putting thoughts into words using language inherently causes inaccuracy. Then you pass that already imperfect expression of your thought through the channel of another language, which adds even more inaccuracy.</p> <p>But don’t worry, language learners! As I described above, I found learning a language to be a process of slowly but certainly moving away from this double-filtering process, developing the new language as an independent means of expressing your thoughts. This process is interesting: as it goes on, you start to suppress the circuit responsible for the other language you’re not actively using at the moment, rather than actively relying them as a mediator. For example, now I find it difficult to text in Korean while speaking to my friends in English.</p> <p>The last thing I want to share here is that the language does not only function as a mere means of expressing your internal thoughts. It also works the other way around: language plays extensive role in interpreting the external world and further shapes how you think, because it becomes the semantic way you use to describe your world.</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4> <p>For all the thoughts I laid out above, I am very interested in solidifying and extending the English-language space in my mind. I would love to learn and discover more diverse ways of describing my internal world using this language, so that my words reflect my inner world with greater resolution, and conversely, so that I can think more broadly through my extended language. I started reading books, mostly memoirs and novels, in English. I took a poetry writing class — the class full of older ladies, mostly Stanford staff members  — and hearing their poetic descriptions of the Stanford campus and the world was such an interesting experience.</p> <p>Lastly, <em>this blog.</em> This project is another effort. An effort with hope that I would be expressing my true heart better and staying closely connected with the people I care about.</p> <p>Finally, dear my fellow language learners: everybody, including native speakers, speak a different version of language. As Wittgenstein discussed, everyone plays a different language game. What we call proficiency is not necessarily about speaking like one particular native speaker with the exact same mental dictionary, tone, accent and voice.</p> <p>We can be proud of how we put our thoughts using our own language, because it is very unique to each of us. That’s the beauty of language.</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <h4 id="acknowledgment">Acknowledgment</h4> <p>Before I sign off, I would like to write a few more words to thank my friends back in Atlanta for being extremely open-minded and understanding.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay"/><category term="language"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with the thought from thoughts to language]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Between Idealism and Reality</title><link href="https://suhee-cho.github.io/blog/2024/idealism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Between Idealism and Reality"/><published>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://suhee-cho.github.io/blog/2024/idealism</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://suhee-cho.github.io/blog/2024/idealism/"><![CDATA[ <p>These are unstructured thoughts on how I came to neuroscience/cognitive science and how my relationship with it has evolved. Hope readers enjoy it (if any).</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <p>At the tender age of 15, I got my first unofficial job at a wedding hall. A school friend had introduced me, saying, “I know the manager. You can just show up. No contracts or paperwork needed.” A few days after washing dishes for six hours straight, I got my first paycheck that was well below minimum wage. I called the manager, argued, and lost miserably. He knew that underage kids without legal documents didn’t want their parents involved. He also knew that using us was cheaper than buying a dishwasher, and that we couldn’t quit despite this unpleasant reality. He was, truly, a competent manager who ran his business in a cost-efficient way.</p> <p>Like many teenagers, my high school life was marked by ambivalence—a mix of anger toward the seemingly unfair world and a strong desire to thrive in it. Although news media and drama series portrayed a college degree as a ladder to success, peers at my school were rarely interested in pursuing it. And that was not necessarily because of bad grades, but rather because making money seemed more practical. “If you go to college, you lose money. But if you get a job, you make money.” Many adults echoed similar sentiments, though in a more organized, experience-based way. Intellectuals, they said, were hypocrites who talked about ideals that didn’t matter in real life and exploited others in the process. They saw education as a corrupting force, yet paradoxically blamed their hardships on not having had access to it. So, is college good or bad? I wasn’t sure.</p> <p>Still, I was an iconoclast who stuck to studying as my path. This stubbornness, which largely shaped my life in hindsight, was not the result of a sophisticated calculation of how much benefit it could bring me in the long run. Rather, it came from something more immediate: concrete solace in momentarily turning my attention away from a chaotic world, filled with things like the competent manager, friends dropping out of school saying there was no hope in school, and the malaise of not knowing which path was right. In fact, I didn’t choose neuroscience out of some grand vision. I stumbled upon a public lecture about action potentials, ion channels, and neurotransmitters, and found myself captivated. The brain, and nature more broadly, seemed to follow rules. There was tangible order that I could grasp if I took some time and effort. So, whenever the world seemed absurd, I immersed myself in a deep sea of scientific imagination. I loved the questions neuroscientists asked. I loved spending time pondering and talking about them. I had a stubborn personality along with a childlike hope: one day, I would become a neuroscientist.</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <p>After a few years of hard work, I got into KAIST. College life was entirely different from high school. For one, none of the students I met had worked for money but rather spent their time learning to play the violin or tennis in high school. That disparity upset me, so I clinged again to consolation of studying. But even neuroscience proved less tidy than I’d envisioned. Many studies once considered “gold standards” were easily refuted and quietly faded from memory. The order I had admired now seemed more fragile. Still, that was fine for me if that’s how science evolves. Or perhaps I should say it’s even more exciting this way. Science is about finding what’s most plausible, rather than what’s definitively true, and there is always room for revision and openness to more sophisticated views.</p> <p>What truly puzzled me was how academia seemed to channel intellectual engagement into narrow, achievement-focused paths. After undergrad, you go to grad school. Then a PhD. Then a job, promotion and tenure. Then awards, patents, and fancy journals. It’s a ladder of accomplishments. Even work that didn’t start with achievement in mind often ends up shaped so, because anything that doesn’t contribute to your CV is often disregarded. What surprised me most was how some researchers didn’t seem to think deeply about their own beliefs when setting hypotheses and developing them into papers. Instead, they leaned toward whatever was likeliest to yield publishable results that would impress editors and reviewers. But where is the joy I had felt as a teenager? That joy was the only reason I chose this path…</p> <div class="dots-divider"></div> <p>Please understand that I’ve just graduated college. My insight is subjective and incomplete, and the story is far from over (I definitely have too few observations to generalize!). This essay is simply a record of my thoughts at this early stage in my career, and I believe it would be fun to see how my thoughts will evolve over time! For now, I have two ideas that I hold onto and would like to clarify here: First, I don’t believe the academic system, or the people within it, are wrong or corrupt. Most are doing their best, and their work genuinely advances the field. Second, and this may seem contradictory to the first, I don’t think my younger self was naïve. That idealistic passion shaped who I am now, and I’m genuinely happy with where I’ve arrived.</p> <p>So, here’s my inconclusive conclusion: I’ll stay sharp on understanding how systems shape people’s behavuor as well as mine. At the same time, I’ll personally try to keep the joy that first drew me to this field. The joy wasn’t professionalized, but was strong enough to push me beyond the boundaries of what people around me thought was normal. If I can protect that spirit, I’ll never regret the day in tenth grade when I decided to become a neuroscientist. I may not change the world, but I can change mine, right?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="personal"/><category term="essay"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My Journey in Academia]]></summary></entry></feed>